<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Katherine Schneider&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Katherine Schneider&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Powered by [Hugo](http://gohugo.io).</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Syrian Crisis- U.S. and Russian Response</title>
      <link>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/syrian-crisis-u-s-and-russian-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/syrian-crisis-u-s-and-russian-response/</guid>
      <description>This post will summarize two articles that provided interesting insights into the positions and actions taken by Russia and the United States, while offering background of the Syrian conflict. The articles used include,
“Armed Conflict in Syria: Overview and U.S.Response” Written by,
Christopher M. Blanchard Coordinator Specialist in Middle Eastern Affairs,
 Carla E. Humud Analyst in Middle Eastern and African Affairs
 Mary Beth D. Nikitin Specialist in Nonproliferation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bar Plots</title>
      <link>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/bar-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/bar-plots/</guid>
      <description>To begin, let’s make sure we have and bring in all the correct packages,
library(Lahman) library(ggplot2) library(sqldf) library(flexdashboard) Now, what information do we want to extract for our bar plot-
query&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;SELECT name,HR FROM Teams WHERE yearID=1980 ORDER BY HR&amp;quot; result&amp;lt;-sqldf(query) Next, in a similar process with previous plots made, let’s turn this information into an easy-to-read bar plot. Today we started to use result$name and introduced coord_flip() to ensure it did not do any additional math between our extracted data and our table</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histograms</title>
      <link>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/histograms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/histograms/</guid>
      <description>These are the pakages we will need to make the intended histogram:
library(Lahman) library(sqldf) library(ggplot2) Making a histogram; First we extracted the data we wanted to appear on our graph
query&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;SELECT weight FROM Master&amp;quot; result&amp;lt;-sqldf(query) From there its similar to making a scatterplot, just approiate alterations where necessary, i.e. introduction of “bin” function
ggplot()+ geom_histogram(data=result,aes(x=weight),color=&amp;quot;yellow&amp;quot;,fill=&amp;quot;white&amp;quot;,bins=50)+ ggtitle(&amp;quot;Body Weight Distribution for Baseball Players&amp;quot;) ## Warning: Removed 854 rows containing non-finite values (stat_bin). </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scatterplots</title>
      <link>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/scatterplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/scatterplots/</guid>
      <description>These are the pakages we will need to make the intended scatterplot;
library(Lahman) library(sqldf) library(ggplot2) Scatterplots were introduced today. The lesson was started with the task of finding all homeruns and strikeouts in the MBL, then narrowing it down to the best homerun records for each player (a sum of 400 or more). This is the extracted data wanted on the scatterplot;
query&amp;lt;-&amp;quot;SELECT playerID,sum(HR) AS career_HR,sum(SO) AS career_SO FROM Batting GROUP BY playerID HAVING sum(HR)&amp;gt;=400&amp;quot; result&amp;lt;-sqldf(query) In order to visualize this into an easy-to-read scatter plot we ran the following;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series</title>
      <link>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://katherineschneider.netlify.com/post/time-series/</guid>
      <description>These are the pakages we will need to make the intended time series plot;
library(Lahman) library(sqldf) library(ggplot2) Now, say we wanted to see progessive change over time- we would contruct a time series graph. In this case we wanted to see Babe Ruths number of homeruns over the years; Note- time is always on the x axis and the changing varaible will be on the y axis Extracting the data;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>